now Dr Lal pathlabs also reported
numbers we quarterly performance from
the company revenues were subdueds
profits dipped to double digits margins
contracted as well but what's the
Outlook as we start another new
Financial year Oman Chanda is managing
director at Dr Lal Path Labs he's
joining us now uh to take questions Mr
Manchester great to have you with us
here good morning thanks very much
Prashant this side
uh so I want to start exactly there with
would you would you like to give out a
explicit Top Line guidance for uh F5 24
I mean that will be most helpful go on
uh good morning uh so I think all I can
say right now is that we are entering
fy24 on a positive note uh FY 23 was uh
one of the difficult years not only for
uh for the company but for entire
industry because uh kovid revenues fell
very sharply to the extent of 85 90 and
that put the entire industry in bit of a
financial sort of management stress
because it was very difficult to pull
back all the cost uh but I think I'm
happy to say that we that's behind us
now we are entering fy24 on a much more
positive note we have a smoother sort of
Baseline
and competitive intensity also in the
business actually has somewhat reduced
what we saw probably a year back I think
overall we are entering fi 24 on a very
positive note
um
uh did a non-covered revenue so covered
revenues fell and that's understandable
but it's not possible to bring down
costs related to that at the same level
in the same Pace uh but it will happen
in fy24 is what you're telling us but
non-covered revenues uh also remain
sluggish could you tell us in a fourth
quarter did you see a decline as
compared to the previous quarter for
that for that segment
yes
yeah I think the last couple of years
we've been seeing a very flatish pattern
between Q3 and Q4 uh Q3 used to be
earlier weaker quarter but last couple
of years I'm noticing that our
q1 Q3 and Q4 are very similar quarter so
I am really not bittered about that but
overall I think Q4 if you look at
Standalone are non-code growths are
fairly okay and uh also one must see
that last two three years one has not
been able to take a price increase for
the first time you took price increase
in the month of February which is also a
positive news because we didn't see much
of resistance coming back from the
market so I think overall I would say
that our ability to take price increase
is much better now than what we were
seeing earlier
we noted that you know that's why I
think the realization per patient went
up to around 770 rupees approximately
since that last price increase got
absorbed do you think that you'll be
taking any more price increases where do
you expect realizations to stabilize
that and also in terms of a volume
growth number some part of the sheet was
expecting a little bit a higher number
in quarter four what kind of volume
growth are you looking at in f524 if you
compare it with f523
let me first address your observation
about Revenue population it has
definitely gone up which is a positive
news uh it's not only just because the
price increase but also if you notice
contribution from bundle packages our
brand name is first fit that is sharply
gone up to 22 that also has contributed
to higher Revenue per patient even
though there is a mixed change also we
are observing because high-end test
portfolio is going much faster uh they
realizations are much higher so all that
is contributing to higher relation per
patient I think our second question is
whether we'd be taking another price
increase probably not yet this just
began in the month of February we would
wait and watch as to how it goes but
obviously some bit of rebalancing is
already happening internal routine test
and high-end test over a period of time
and we will continue to look at this
area as well as we go along
okay that's about the prices and volumes
what is the broad number you can guide
uh for f524
yeah if you look at last three four
years cagr we are noticing that our
average volume growth is about eight to
nine percent and I think we're hopeful
that we should continue to keep keep
that number intact uh you also should
see that volumes actually have two
aspects one is a patient visit
uh that's a number which is reported
right now but we are also seeing a very
good growth in number of tests per
patient which is contributing higher
sample growth
so I think there's a bit of an interplay
between number of tests per patient and
the number of visits so I think overall
we are very confident of sustaining the
growth that we have experienced in the
past
all right and uh swashfest as you
mentioned that's around 22 percent now
where do you see that number ahead
because it's been growing quite well and
it's you know helping the overall
numbers as well
yeah I think it's clearly providing
value to virtually every stakeholder
even it's very easy for medical
fraternity to prescribe this test uh
swast fit uh it probably covers all the
liver function kidney function and all
these cells together it's a great value
for money for the patient as well
because in one go they are able to test
uh tests related to many organs and for
us also it simplifies the business
operations because one Cube just gets
loaded on the machine and you can do all
these tests so I think Market is clearly
moving towards uh where uh screening
packages are really gaining ground and
there's other part of the business which
is illness part which is highly
specialized part I think I can clearly
see the Divide between routine tests
which is bundle and high-end tests which
are prescribed by high-end doctors so I
I am very bullish about this whole
bundle package is going forward what's
the price of swasfit now for the for the
package now
oh it's actually the multiple price
points depending on the basic going up
to very high end so I think it ranges
between 800 to 3 4 000 bucks so but
there are multiple price points at which
we operate
good morning I want to get your sense on
the Suburban business as well and how
that's shaping up how much contribution
You're Expecting and I believe margins
for Suburban but somewhere in the
vicinity of 12 percent
have they improved now and that brings
me to the overall picture I mean also
give us a sense of guidance on uh fy24
uh composite Blended margins for Dr Lal
Path Labs now that you're saying
competitive intensity is reducing can we
start seeing margins get back to
somewhere close to the earlier highs
uh let me first address the Suburban
piece I think we are fairly confident of
as we go into FY 24 first available I
think the last year was we've achieved
couple of things one is of course a
transition from uh earlier sort of
management structure to a very
professional structure now we've also
launched a very big Reference Lab in the
city of Mumbai and overall uh if you if
you study data of suburban last year uh
it had virtually 50 of turnover coming
from kovit and actually we manage this
whole transition of uh forward virtually
falling from 113 crore to nine crore and
pulling back cost I think we are fairly
pleased with our performance of managing
ebitda or with such a high fall of poet
and now it mimics uh what this business
was pre-covered times and we we know
that this business didn't have very high
margin compared to what we have in the
parent company but 155 crore of Base 80
of it coming from Mumbai City I think
it's a very great platform for us to go
go in the region of course
not at all uh sort of debating that just
want to understand what's the
differential between Suburban margins
and parent company margins and going
forward when you put the two together FY
24 what's the margin Outlook
is still in the range of about 24 25
uh we know that Suburban is still about
12 it is a bit diluted but it's all
baked in the f520
three margins so we continue to hope
that fi 24 will be very similar to what
we've delivered last year
okay all right
and uh folio will be 20 around 25
margins right yeah in that range of 20
25 train okay got that thank you very
much appreciate you joining in it's
always a pleasure speaking with you sir
good luck uh so that's uh Dr Lal Path
Labs with perspective on what the future
holds for them well